qantaspoints.com 2017-09-15

# Privacy Statement | Qantas

### Privacy Statement

## Introduction

Back to list

This Privacy Statement explains in general terms how Qantas* collects, holds, uses and discloses your personal information under the Australian Privacy Principles.

Specific information about how we collect, use and disclose the personal information of members of our Loyalty Programs*** is contained in the section titled 'Loyalty Programs'.

We may amend this Privacy Statement as our business requirements or the law changes. Any changes to this Privacy Statement will be updated on qantas.com. We may also issue specific privacy collection notices from time-to-time relating to particular products or services.

This Privacy Statement does not apply to Qantas' employee records.

## Information we collect

Back to list

The types of personal information that we collect about you will depend on our relationship with you, the circumstances of collection and the type of service you request from us. The personal information may include:

  * Your name, gender, date of birth, contact details, passport details, image and answer to a security question (for example, mother's maiden name);
  * Details related to your flights and other travel details, including your preferences with respect to your travel on our flights;
  * Your dietary requirements and health issues which you provide to us in connection with your use of our products and services;
  * Payment details (such as credit/debit card number and expiry date) provided in connection with the purchase of our products and services;
  * If you use our website or mobile applications, your geo-location, IP address, mobile telephone number or ID and details of any third party sites that you may have accessed; and
  * Loyalty Program membership number and membership details of any other loyalty programs.

If you are an employee travelling or obtaining other products or services in relation to one of our corporate, business or government clients, we may also collect information about your role with the client, your employment type, your employee number, your start date with the client and details of any employer paid travel arrangements.

If you are a shareholder we (or our agent) will collect certain details about you for registration purposes, such as your name, address, number of shares held, tax file number and bank account details. We are required to maintain a register of shareholders under the Corporations Act 2001 (Cth).

## How we collect information

Back to list

We may collect personal information about you when you use our products and services or purchase our goods, make or update a booking to use our services, register to receive our newsletters or other communications, register to be part of one of our programs, tell us about your preferences when flying with us, fill out medical and other forms associated with your travel, enter into one of our competitions, visit our websites, complete one of our surveys or otherwise interact with us. As well as collecting information directly from you, there may be occasions when we collect information about you from a third party. These third parties may include:

  * Travel agents and other people who make or update travel or freight bookings on your behalf, or otherwise interact with us on your behalf, including when you make an inquiry with a travel agent but do not proceed to a booking;
  * Our Service providers such as operators of our corporate travel functions or call centres and organisations that issue a Qantas Air Waybill for the carriage of your freight;
  * Third parties that run competitions and other promotions for us or for which we are the sponsor;
  * Third parties that provide us with marketing leads;
  * Immigration, customs, border security and other regulatory authorities;
  * Other companies within Qantas and companies in the Jetstar Group;
  * Your share broker when you purchase shares in Qantas Airways Limited; and
  * Third parties for, with or from whom we provide or receive marketing and data analysis services.

## How we use your personal information

Back to list

We may use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * To provide and administer our goods and services, including verifying your identity; contacting you about your orders and bookings and travel, freight and other arrangements; processing payments; training our staff; testing our systems; and managing your interaction with our suppliers;
  * To provide and operate our competitions, promotions and events;
  * To distribute our newsletters and other communications either ourselves or with the assistance of third party services providers;
  * For customer support, including resolving and providing assistance for mishandled or missing baggage claims or responding to other enquiries or requests;
  * To ensure the safety and security of all passengers when travelling with us, including investigating security and screening issues;
  * To facilitate your participation in the Loyalty Programs and loyalty programs of other program partners;
  * To conduct marketing activities, for our products and services, or products and services of third parties, and to conduct market and other research to improve our products, services and marketing activities and generating consumer insights which may include combining personal information from third parties or public sources (eg Census data);
  * To register any shareholding you may have in Qantas Airways Limited and to contact you in relation to that shareholding; and
  * To maintain records and comply with our legal obligations, including laws relating to immigration, customs and border security.

## Disclosure of personal information

Back to list

We may disclose your personal information to others in connection with the sale and provision of our travel and freight services and our Loyalty Programs, including:

  * Other carriers for codeshare and transfer arrangements;
  * **one** world alliance airlines, and other airline and non-airline partners participating in the Loyalty Programs for use in the operation and marketing of those programs; and
  * Our service providers, including those providing billing services, catering services, chauffeur services, airport lounge operations, and ground handling services (such as check-in agents, freight handling and special assistance).

We may also disclose your personal information to our suppliers and third parties that perform other services for us in connection with the sale and provision of all our goods and services, including third parties who:

  * Provide customer service and operate call centres;
  * Operate some corporate and government travel sales and fulfilment functions;
  * Conduct market research and analysis;
  * Provide marketing services;
  * Provide information technology services such as airline related systems, data storage, distribution services, passenger and freight booking and processing systems, communication networks, software and system development, maintenance and support, and information processing, analysis and reporting;
  * Provide services in the course of investigating a complaint or a security incident; and
  * Manage our share registry.

We may also disclose your personal information to comply with our legal obligations, including to various law enforcement agencies, regulatory authorities and governments around the world and their service providers for security, customs and immigration purposes. 

Your information may also be shared between companies within Qantas and Jetstar Airways Pty Ltd and its subsidiaries. 

If you are an employee of one of our corporate, business or government clients and are travelling for work purposes on a ticket purchased by your employer, we may also disclose your travel details and any information associated with your travel (such as incident reports) to your employer. 

Our share register is available for inspection by the public as required under the Corporations Act 2001 (Cth). The information collected in connection with your shareholding may also be disclosed to regulatory bodies such as the Australian Taxation Office, as well as to print service providers and mail houses.

## Loyalty Programs

Back to list

Information on our Loyalty Program databases (including information about users of products and services available to members of our Loyalty Programs) is used for additional purposes to those outlined in the section titled 'How we use your personal information'. 

One of the primary purposes of these programs is to provide and market enhanced products and services to you, including the products and services of our partners and other third parties who we believe may have products and services in which you would be interested. Other purposes include assessing membership applications; awarding program points; confirming eligibility for and providing services associated with these programs; providing enhanced and personalised benefits and services; understanding your interests and hobbies to enhance your use of the programs; improving our services and customer service, including by means of research, behavioural analytics, product development and planning; and operational management of the programs.

For these purposes, additional information is collected by us through your registration with, and participation in, the Loyalty Programs (including your application for, and use of, a Qantas Frequent Flyer linked credit card, Qantas Cash card or any other benefit). This additional information may include information such as country of residence, seating and other travel preferences, leisure and sports interests, and information about how you earn and use your points. This information may be collected from you directly or from third parties providing services for the Loyalty Programs or our program partners, such as when you register through one of our program partners or transact with them. 

In addition to the disclosures outlined in the section 'Disclosure of Information to Third Parties', Qantas may disclose this information to partner airlines, oneworld alliance airlines, and non-airline program partners for the purposes outlined above. The information may also be disclosed to any third party providing services for the Loyalty Programs (including products and services available to members), including assisting us in determining your eligibility for, and providing, these products and services, administering the programs, handling and processing membership applications and operating our call and service centres. 

If you are an employee travelling or obtaining other products or services in relation to one of our Qantas Business Rewards members, we may also collect information about your role with the member, your employment type, your employee number, your start date with the member and details of any employer paid travel arrangements. If you are travelling for work purposes on a ticket purchased by your employer, we may disclose your travel details and any information associated with your travel (such as incident reports) to your employer. 

When you are logged into your Loyalty Program account, Qantas may also keep logs of your use of qantas.com. This information may include date and time of visit, Loyalty Program membership number, membership status, surname, location and actions, for example, pages viewed and pages submitted. We may use this information to monitor the use of, and improve, the information and functions on qantas.com, understand your preferences and provide you with information about our products and services and our partners' products and services which we think may interest you. If you are a Loyalty Program member and are logged into your account, the information we collect may be linked with your personal information.

When you apply for and use a Qantas Frequent Flyer linked credit card or Qantas Cash card, we may also collect your personal information from, and disclose your personal information to:

  * Customer verification companies for ID checking and due diligence as required for all financial products;
  * Our service providers who manage, and provide customer service for, these financial products; and
  * Our card partners to award points for eligible activities.

Membership of and participation in our Loyalty Programs is subject to the respective programs' terms and conditions which can be viewed online at qantas.com.

In addition to the specific information above, Loyalty Program members should read the following general sections:

## How we use cookies

Back to list

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on the web browser on your computer. This website and associated websites (including those you reach by clicking on advertising) may store cookies on your web browser.

You can visit our viewing tips page to see if you have cookies enabled in your browser. You can also check this page to see how we use cookies and to enable or disable cookies in your browser.

## How we hold information and keep it secure

Back to list

We hold your personal information in a combination of hard copy and electronic files. We use third party information system providers who may store or have access to your personal information. 

We may combine personal information we receive about you with other information we hold about you. This includes information received from our partners or third parties. 

When you book flights or access your Loyalty Program membership information, a secure server is used. Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encrypts the information you send through this website.

## Disclosure of information overseas

Back to list

In the course of providing our services, we may disclose your personal information (including personal information of our Loyalty Programs' members) to companies within Qantas, subsidiaries of Jetstar Airways Pty Ltd and third parties located overseas who assist us in providing our travel (including transit) and freight services and associated services, and law enforcement agencies, regulatory authorities and governments for security, customs and immigration purposes. These parties may be located in any country to which you send freight or travel to or through with us or our partner airlines.

We may also disclose your personal information to data processors (including operators of global travel distribution systems), customer service providers and managers of our financial products located overseas. The countries in which these third parties are located include the United Kingdom, the United States and Germany.

## Access and correction of information about you

Back to list

If you would like to request access to, or correction of, your personal information we hold about you, please contact us using the contact details in the section titled 'Our contact details'.

We will provide you with access to the information we hold about you, including for the purpose of correcting or updating that information, unless there is an exception which applies under the Australian Privacy Principles.

We may recover from you our reasonable costs of supplying you with access to this information. However, we will not charge you for the making of the request or to correct or update your personal information.

Your request to provide access to this information will be dealt with within a reasonable time.

If we refuse to provide you with access to, or correct, the information, we will notify you of our reasons for the refusal to the extent required and how you may complain about the refusal.

Loyalty Program members can update their profile information online or by contacting us using the details in the section titled 'Our contact details'.

## Privacy complaints and further information 

Back to list

If you have a concern about your privacy or you have any query on how your personal information is collected or used please contact us using the details below. We will respond to your query or complaint within a reasonable time. 

If you are not satisfied with our response, you may also contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.

## Our contact details

Back to list

You can contact us by completing the form located at:

[qantas.com/privacyquestionsThis link will open in a new window.](https://www.qantas.com/privacyquestions)

 **or by writing to:**

Qantas Customer Care  
Qantas Airways Limited  
10 Bourke Road  
Mascot NSW 2020  
Australia

* Qantas means Qantas Airways Limited and its related bodies corporate, excluding companies in the Jetstar Group**, Wishlist Holdings Limited and Qantas Superannuation Limited.  
** Jetstar Group means Jetstar Airways Pty Ltd and its subsidiaries, and all Jetstar branded entities.  
*** Loyalty Programs means the Qantas Frequent Flyer Program (including Frequent Flyer linked credit cards and Qantas Cash cards), Qantas Business Rewards, Qantas Assure and the Qantas Club.
